<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://neillrobson.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://neillrobson.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-10-25T20:45:49+00:00</updated><id>https://neillrobson.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Neill Robson’s Website</title><subtitle>The blog and portfolio of a software developer.
</subtitle><author><name>Neill Robson</name></author><entry><title type="html">Grad School Like I’m Five: Buffer Overflow</title><link href="https://neillrobson.com/blog/2020/11/23/grad-school-like-im-five/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Grad School Like I’m Five: Buffer Overflow" /><published>2020-11-23T20:25:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-11-23T20:25:00+00:00</updated><id>https://neillrobson.com/blog/2020/11/23/grad-school-like-im-five</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://neillrobson.com/blog/2020/11/23/grad-school-like-im-five/">&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;, I’ve written approximately 6,000 lines of code over the course of the past four months (welcome to grad school!).
The question is, can I explain all of the stuff I wrote? &lt;!--more--&gt;
Over the next few blog posts, I’ll be trying to present a high-level overview of some of the most interesting concepts that I’ve learned this past semester.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How high-level, you ask?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal is to explain these concepts to a five-year-old.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only will this audience choice keep these blog posts short and sweet, it will also help me reassure myself that the boatloads of information I consumed throughout this semester did not simply fall out of my other ear!
And, of course, I hope that you, the reader, find these snippets more entertaining to read than your average textbook chapter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this inaugural episode, we will cover… &lt;strong&gt;Buffer Overflow&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-problem&quot;&gt;The Problem&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine we’re sitting across from each other, with an empty table between us.
The tabletop is wiped so clean, you can see the reflection of the overhead light in the white plastic.
I give you a crayon, and I ask you to draw a cat.
What do you do?
If you’re following my instructions, you’ll probably start drawing a cat directly on the table.
If I’m a self-respecting grown-up, I’ll probably respond by scolding you for drawing on furniture.
But you were only doing what you were told to do!
Grown-ups are so unfair, am I right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, I’ll give you a piece of paper: unlined and white, a blank slate for your work of art.
I set it down in front of you, and ask you once again to draw a cat.
And you do!
It’s a cool cat that you draw, and I’m impressed, so I ask you to draw another.
And another.
And another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://pics.me.me/hey-girl-isaw-you-coloring-inside-the-linesearlierandivejust-gotto-say-7937983.png&quot; alt=&quot;Elementary-aged boy uttering a pickup line to girl&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a while, you mention how tired you are, and ask to go play with friends for a while.
Happy with your work, I allow you to go, and I reach down to grab the paper with your fantastic cat drawings.
There’s only one problem…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.kenarry.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/how-to-get-dry-erase-marker-off-the-wall2.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Whiteboard with dry erase markings on the wall&quot; title=&quot;Mom's face when she sees you've crossed the line&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Mom's face when she sees you've crossed the line&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ve drawn so many cats that you ran out of space on the paper and got markings on the table once again.
With white paper on a white plastic table, who’s to blame you for overstepping those boundaries?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a similar way, computers have a large table on which they can write and draw.
Usually, someone like you and me will lay down pieces of paper for the computer, so that when it draws cats for the cat-drawing program, those cats won’t end up on the table or on anyone else’s paper sitting nearby.
But the computer can’t tell the difference between your paper, my paper, its paper, or the table, so unless we are &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; specific about the size of what we tell it to draw, it has no problem drawing all over everyone else’s work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of that, most people give computers enormous amounts of instructions in advance.
Although I just told you to draw one cat at a time (maybe ten cats in all), professional computer people get paid lots of money to tell computers to draw &lt;em&gt;billions&lt;/em&gt; of cats at once in the fastest way possible.
It’s like your math teacher writing up a billion-problem multiplication drill the night before, handing it to you the next morning, and leaving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.1989generationinitiative.org/j/2020/07/times-table-worksheets-activity-shelter-multiplication-drill-counting-money-kindergarten.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;five-minute multiplication drill&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s no way to know in advance if you’ll write beyond the lines at some point in that greuling process!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-solution-&quot;&gt;The Solution (?)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So after cleaning the poor table of all your crayon marks, I decide to fix the problem by using a new type of paper.
This paper, rather than being pure white, has a thick red border around the edges.
We’ll call this border the “red zone.”
Now, when you’re drawing, I can see when your crayon hits the red zone, and choose to change my instructions to you so that you don’t venture beyond that zone.
(Of course, you could also use that red zone to guide yourself, but computers aren’t as smart as you are.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a similar way, I can mark certain edges in the computer’s table (we call that table “memory” in the computer) as dangerous regions (red zones).
Whenever a computer tries to write anything on that zone, the programmer can be notified and jump in to change the instructions (the “program”) so that the computer doesn’t venture past that edge any longer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.simplemost.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/7275464206_72432c61cd_o_sidewalk-bumps.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Child stepping on sidewalk bumps&quot; title=&quot;We have &amp;quot;red zones&amp;quot; in real life too. Sometimes they're other colors, like yellow.&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;We have &quot;red zones&quot; in real life too. Sometimes they're other colors, like yellow.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one should be fooled that this strategy solves all of our problems, though.
The red zone is not &lt;em&gt;preventing&lt;/em&gt; our computer from drawing outside its region—only warning us of its error.
Furthermore, I could easily instruct the computer (or you!) to draw something “new” far outside the bounds of the paper.
For example, say I want you to draw a cloud in the sky above the various cats.
In that case, you could draw that entire cloud without ever touching the red zone that I’ve designated.
When I’m watching you, it’s easy to spot the error, but again, remember that most big-shot computer programmers send in tasks like billion-question multiplication quizzes in advance.
They don’t bother to watch every calculation, but rely on looking at the red zone after the fact to see if their instructions need to be edited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could make larger red zones to catch more of these over-steps, but if I make the red zone too big, then no one would be able to draw anything &lt;em&gt;outside&lt;/em&gt; of the massive red zone!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that’s buffer overflows and red zones in a nutshell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those over the age of five might be interested in the open-source tool that I used during my studies to implement a red-zone-based buffer overflow detector.
If so, definitely check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dynamorio.org/&quot;&gt;DynamoRIO&lt;/a&gt; runtime code manipulation system and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Xuhpclab/DrCCTProf&quot;&gt;DrCCTProf&lt;/a&gt; call path profiling tool built atop DynamoRIO.
I cannot yet release my own code to the public for viewing, as grades for the class are still being calculated, but pending the professor’s permission I will definitely update this blog post with links for interested parties!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you found this little explanation entertaining and informational.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>neill</name></author><category term="college" /><category term="software" /><summary type="html">According to GitHub, I’ve written approximately 6,000 lines of code over the course of the past four months (welcome to grad school!). The question is, can I explain all of the stuff I wrote?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Book Review: The Circle, by Dave Eggers</title><link href="https://neillrobson.com/blog/2018/02/24/book-review-the-circle-by-dave-eggers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Book Review: The Circle, by Dave Eggers" /><published>2018-02-24T15:13:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-02-24T15:13:00+00:00</updated><id>https://neillrobson.com/blog/2018/02/24/book-review-the-circle-by-dave-eggers</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://neillrobson.com/blog/2018/02/24/book-review-the-circle-by-dave-eggers/">&lt;p&gt;For the first time I can remember in a long while, I did not have the endurance to make it through a book. &lt;em&gt;The Circle&lt;/em&gt; was patronizing, immature, and (as others have already mentioned) offered nothing new to the conversation. &lt;!--more--&gt; Halfway through the book, I could not recall a single plot development that could not be recreated precisely (often down to the phrasing of the words) from current news or social media. Some speculative literature provides an insightful reflection on human nature; others grant an escape from the world’s worries; Eggers manages to to neither in his work, using such an explicit and leaden pen that one might draw parallels to reading one’s own social media feed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third-person limited point of view tries desperately to inspire the reader’s empathy towards the protagonist, but the narrative thrashes between vapid predictability and deplorable decision-making. Typically, a character’s weaknesses and vulnerabilities evoke some measure of compassion from the audience, but I found no such sympathy for a protagonist so passive and malleable to her own surroundings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Far from edifying or subtly cautionary, the mature content smacked of pretentious gossip and schoolboy fantasies. Was Eggers’s intention to copy the fatuous desires and half-baked relationships of modern society to further condemn the digital age? He only managed to add a veneer of erotic language to lessons that anyone mature enough to read his book could glean just as easily from turning on the television.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In submission, the portion of this book that I forced down my gullet did resonate with my own past experience. The fears and fascinations, challenges and trials that the fictional community faces are present with glaring radiance in my history, and I am by no means worthy of denouncing the lifestyle that this book attempts to critique. But if &lt;em&gt;The Circle&lt;/em&gt; wanted to be a parable, it failed miserably: those of us who would benefit from the perspective this book attempts to provide would more likely find the reading experience an act of navel-gazing, while those capable of gleaning the moral by and large have already discovered it from reflection and experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe I did not represent the intended audience for Eggers, but to dismiss oneself as inappropriate to judge a work that one found repulsive is a self-pitying cop-out. Dave, I want to receive the message you are trying to express, but please instruct me as an adult would exhort an ignorant child: the sources from which I can revel in darkness with fellow miscreants are, as you say, already far to prevalent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you read the book? Watched the movie? (I haven’t yet… should I?) Whether you loved it, hated it, or fall anywhere in between, I would enjoy hearing your opinions in the comments below!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Neill Robson</name></author><category term="literature" /><category term="personal" /><summary type="html">For the first time I can remember in a long while, I did not have the endurance to make it through a book. The Circle was patronizing, immature, and (as others have already mentioned) offered nothing new to the conversation.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Infamous Liebster Award</title><link href="https://neillrobson.com/blog/2018/01/28/the-infamous-liebster-award/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Infamous Liebster Award" /><published>2018-01-28T19:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-01-28T19:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://neillrobson.com/blog/2018/01/28/the-infamous-liebster-award</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://neillrobson.com/blog/2018/01/28/the-infamous-liebster-award/">&lt;p&gt;As an encouragement to continue sharing my thoughts and experiences online, a person near and dear to my heart nominated me for &lt;a href=&quot;https://theglobalaussie.com/liebster-award-2018/&quot;&gt;the Liebster Award&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://theglobalaussie.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/More-Flowers.png&quot; alt=&quot;Liebster Award Logo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First and foremost, I highly recommend that you check out the blog of my nominator, &lt;a href=&quot;https://volarconmigo.wordpress.com/2018/01/07/liebster-award/&quot;&gt;Further Up and Further In&lt;/a&gt; by La Creadora Fantasma. Like myself, LCF is just beginning to learn how to record her own thoughts and inspire others through online publishing, and I am eager to watch her blossom both professionally and creatively through this experience. Keep it up!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it turns out, the “rules” of nomination for the Liebster Award are slightly different from year to year: since 2018 just recently kicked off its opening act, I’ll try and satisfy both the rules given to me by my nominator and the new rules published by the originator. The links to both rulesets are given above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s go!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;intention-explained&quot;&gt;Intention Explained&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why do I write blogs?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My journey began when I took a trip abroad to Hangzhou, China, and was seeking a way to memorialize that unique experience and share it with friends and family back home. Being a quixotic techie with a dogged proclivity toward independence, I threw together a self-hosted website on which I built a resume page in spartan HTML/CSS and a &lt;a href=&quot;https://ghost.org/&quot;&gt;Ghost blog&lt;/a&gt; for recording my time in China. Since then, I’ve spent much more time investing in the website’s technology rather than its content (form over function–an incorrigible flaw against which I battle), and have most recently settled on a &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll site&lt;/a&gt; hosted on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; (a platform to help software developers track their code and collaborate) and managed with &lt;a href=&quot;http://prose.io/&quot;&gt;Prose&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2018/01/the-infamous-liebster-award/jekyll.png&quot; alt=&quot;Github and Jekyll&quot; title=&quot;Jekyll static website generator, plus Github Pages hosting: A match made in an evil genius's lab.&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Jekyll static website generator, plus Github Pages hosting: A match made in an evil genius's lab.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, technologies aside, why do I still strive to immortalize my thoughts in text, and publish them online for the world to see? In truth, my motivation comes down to my love for storytelling: using narratives in every form to build connections with others. From the color palletes of the websites I build to the tension of the piano’s vibrations, from the worlds invented through extemporized theatrical performance to the themes shared through a video game, I am in love with communication–especially through non-traditional media. Building a website and contribuing to a blog is one way I believe that I can combine my two somewhat divergent passions–software development and narrative creation–into a single product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also like being able to save and revise drafts of my thoughts: a practice that most other forms of online social media don’t necessarily allow!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;questions-answered&quot;&gt;Questions Answered&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will now attempt to answer the eleven inquiries of my nominator, La Creadora Fantasma:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Apple, Android, Microsoft, or Linux software?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;You’re killing me already! My knee-jerk response is Linux, because I’ve grown up using various Linux distributions for most of my journey so far as a computer scientist and I value the power and freedom of a community in which everyone is able to contribute to the functional development of the software system.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;That said, as I continue to grow in my understanding of various computer technologies, companies, and cultures, I am also beginning to take into account the pragmatic realities of the field. “Open Source” does not necessarily imply an open and inclusive development community. It doesn’t always yield accessible software, and the provided products and services often fail to bring food to the table of their contributors. There is a time for everything, and a season for every activity under the heavens&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;; free and open-source software has an important place in our community, but it is not the answer to all technological woes.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;From a practical perspective, I actually find myself leaning slightly toward Microsoft. Although I am perhaps least familiar with system administration and software development on Windows, I find Microsoft’s recent actions as a company pleasantly surprising and admirable. They seem eager to make their products accessible and open both to developers (who desire clear documentation and transparent sources) and end users (who desire dependability and elegant functionality). Microsoft doesn’t exhibit the vertical integration of their products and services that Apple does (allowing Apple to provide beautiful interfaces to their customers), but in relaxing their hold on the reins, Microsoft forms better relationships with their developer community. Microsoft still keeps much of their software closed-source, but without doing so they would struggle to make ends meet in order to deliver the high-quality services that end users have come to expect.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2018/01/the-infamous-liebster-award/Microsoft-logo_rgb_c-gray.png&quot; alt=&quot;Microsoft logo circa 2018&quot; title=&quot;A pretty (flat) logo&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;A pretty (flat) logo&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;So, long story short: In a perfect world, Linux. In this world, Microsoft!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you could play any instrument (other than one you already play), what would it be?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;I would definitely choose an instrument that I could carry with me, and perferrably one with which I could sing along. A guitar, despite its simplicity, would be ideal for these requirements! But since portability is more important to me than the ability to sing, I would also seriously consider a harmonica, because it could be a meditation and respite that could literally fit in my pocket.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Herbal, green, black, or white tea?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;I think I’ll have to go with the only choice on the list that isn’t, biologically speaking, tea: the variety of potentials in herbal drinks are what cause me to choose them as my favorite. Of course, one can create concoctions of tea leaves infused with herbs and spices as well, making herbal drinks a perfectly valid option on the list, although I suppose the choice is a bit of a cop-out response as I’m defining it to encompass every other option.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;If I had to choose a type of tea leaf, I would probably choose green tea, because of my lovely experience with Longjing tea in Hangzhou, Zhejiang, China (which you can read more about &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2016/06/15/the-tea/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What was your favorite song as a small kid?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;I don’t remember having a single favorite song. However, there were several songs that stood out as hallmarks of my musical “coming-of-age”:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;The first song I remember falling in love with as a performance piece (on the piano) was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=d020hcWA_Wg&quot;&gt;Clocks by Coldplay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;The first song I ever purchased was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Y6ljFaKRTrI&quot;&gt;Still Alive by Jonathan Coulton&lt;/a&gt;. I also ended up parodying this song as a goodbye gift for the music teacher who directed the theatre production that was pivotal in maturing me emotionally and socially.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2018/01/the-infamous-liebster-award/chell.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The protagonist of Portal&quot; title=&quot;Fan art of Portal--the video game in which Jonathan Coulton's song was featured&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Fan art of Portal--the video game in which Jonathan Coulton's song was featured&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Speaking of that show, I am quite fond of several songs in the soundtrack of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLnbBAvpTGon8EN_eh_zALsb7dxPy-ttnd&quot;&gt;HONK Jr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;The first song I ever performed for a romantic interest was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gynYtBmYlnk&quot;&gt;The Pout-Pout Fish&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;And by far the most important, this song has grown up with me since elementary school as a vivid reminder of God’s relationship with me. Even as an adult it brings tears to my eyes remembering all the situations God carried me through with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cROXxgPMzHA&quot;&gt;this song&lt;/a&gt; in my mind.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What is the best joke you’ve ever heard?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I hate telling puns to kleptomaniacs; they always take things literally.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do you know what a viola is?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Yeah… Isn’t it a string instrument that specializes in producing tones between the ranges of a violin and cello? I’m purposely not going to look up whether I’m right or not to preserve the innocence of my potentially incorrect and offensive answer.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2018/01/the-infamous-liebster-award/viola.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;viola&quot; title=&quot;Something like this, I think&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Something like this, I think&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Have you ever been out of the country? If so, where?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;I’ve been to China (Shameless plug! Read more about the experience on this blog!) and the Caribbean. I would only consider the former experience to be true “cultural immersion,” as the trip to the Caribbean was simply a week-long vacation to a beautiful (but somewhat isolated) resort. It was a wonderful experience nonetheless!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What are some inside family quotes that you’ll never forget?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;In my younger and more self-conscious years, I hated the word “play” when it came to my social interactions with friends. My dad would sometimes reference a “play date” in which I participated, or asked if I would invite some classmates over to “play” after I finished my homework. My answer was invariably, “No! It isn’t called ‘playing’! It’s ‘hanging out’!”&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Well, my dad took a while to get the picture, but he somehow found the compassion and patience to accept my ridicules and attempt to change his perfectly appropriate vocabulary. Bless his heart; that pursuit had deleterious consequences.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;One evening, as a friend and I were enjoying dinner, I asked my dad if my friend could just stay overnight so we could have more time together. Eager to encourage my social interactions (of which I did not have many), my dad readily called up my friend’s parents to organize the evening. “Hi Rick,” he began. “This is Forrest, Neill’s dad. I was wondering if you would be willing– uh, I mean, could Jacob and Neill have a–”&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Dad was struggling to find the socially acceptable term for the request: he was sure that the phrase “sleep-over” was eschewed by the younger crowd. What was the word for “hanging out” overnight? Finally, in a well-intentioned epiphany of vocabulary, my dad sputtered,&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;…Could Jacob and Neill have a &lt;strong&gt;HANG&lt;/strong&gt;-over tonight?!&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Needless to say, Jacob did not spend the night at the Robson household that evening.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Best board game? Best video game?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Although I’ve never played a full session before, I have always venerated the Japanese board game &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Go_game&quot;&gt;Go&lt;/a&gt; for its simplicity and stunning depth of strategy. There is only one type of piece, and they never move once placed, yet it took exponentially more computing power for artificial intelligence to beat a human at Go than it did for the game of Chess, with its sundry rules and moves.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Best video game is, without the shadow of a doubt, &lt;a href=&quot;http://store.steampowered.com/app/210970/The_Witness/&quot;&gt;The Witness&lt;/a&gt;. It is a marvellous tapestry outlining human intelligence and philosophy, and a shining example of nonverbal communication. It is the one video game that I believe would have engaged C.S. Lewis, Steve Jobs, and Douglas Hofstadter alike.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2018/01/the-infamous-liebster-award/witness.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;logo for The Witness&quot; title=&quot;Beautiful.&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Beautiful.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How do you feel about autocorrect when texting?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;I’ve personally turned it off on my phone, because I like to make a habit of proofreading whatever I write (even if it’s just a text message). However, I also readily admit that this practice decreases the efficiency of my communication with others and that the misunderstandings arising from autocorrect are sometimes more valuable lessons than simply fixing typos in the first place. It all depends on your audience, I suppose!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If someone gave you a free, two-way ticket to Mars would you go?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Actually, I think I would! Now, I would still want a year or so to get all of my affairs in order and make sure that my family and friends are all comfortable (!) with the decision. But considering the scientific and psychological advances that humanity would approach through such an experience, if some space-exploring entity deemed me fit to take such a journey, I would happily spend a significant part of my life exploring God’s creation in a way that no one else to this day has been privileged to do.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;facts-delivered&quot;&gt;Facts Delivered&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;My favorite ingredient in any dish (where it is appropriate, of course) is the caper.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I drove my date to the senior prom in my grandfather’s 1995 Oldsmobile Cutlass Ciera.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’ve remapped my keyboard so that the &lt;code&gt;capslock&lt;/code&gt; key acts as &lt;code&gt;esc&lt;/code&gt; when tapped and as &lt;code&gt;ctrl&lt;/code&gt; when held down along with another key. My left &lt;code&gt;ctrl&lt;/code&gt; key is mapped to &lt;code&gt;capslock&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;My first paying job was acting as the cow mascot for Chick-fil-A. I had to quit because I grew too tall for the suit.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2018/01/the-infamous-liebster-award/chick-fil-a-cow-day-2013.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A Chick-fil-A cow mascot&quot; title=&quot;Is that me?! Wouldn't you like to know...&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Is that me?! Wouldn't you like to know...&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The first programming language I took classes and achieved fluency in is &lt;a href=&quot;http://jsoftware.com/&quot;&gt;J&lt;/a&gt;. My teacher was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/henry-rich-5b7503131/&quot;&gt;Henry Rich&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When I took an ideology test in high school, measuring my political views on a spectrum of -72 (left/liberal) to +72 (right/conservative), I received a stunning +2. Since then, my views haven’t changed much: last time I took the test, I had migrated to +6.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I have never crashed a motor vehicle (knock on wood!).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The latest I have ever stayed awake is 3am: I was infuriated because I could not connect to a Raspberry Pi headless (without a monitor). I have never pulled a true all-nighter.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2018/01/the-infamous-liebster-award/rpi.png&quot; alt=&quot;The Raspberry Pi motherboard, shown to sacle.&quot; title=&quot;I've never tasted a real raspberry pie before: only the bitter tears of bootstrapping one.&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;I've never tasted a real raspberry pie before: only the bitter tears of bootstrapping one.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I prefer colder climates over warmer ones: not because I like being outside in the cold, but because I love the feeling and smell of indoor heating (stove, fireplace, etc) more than the atmosphere made by indoor cooling (fans, air conditioning).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One of my childhood comfort foods was white rice with cupcake sprinkles mixed in.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I used to be terrified of my elementary school’s janitor, because he was from China and could not speak English well. Being unable to communicate was a prodigious fear for me, so I never talked to him.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;questions-asked&quot;&gt;Questions Asked&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you could replace all the water on Earth with one other homogeneous chemical substance–with the assurance that life on Earth could still survive exactly as it does now by drinking that chemical–what substance would you choose and why?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are three adjectives that your worst enemy would use to describe you?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’re going to a desert island and you get to take one book with you, but I get to rip out my choice of 50% of the pages before giving it to you. What book do you choose?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All world governments are now replaced with arbitrary Fortune 500 companies. You have your choice of living under any one of them. Which do you choose?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’re sentenced to death row, and given the choice of your last meal. What do you choose?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What is your favorite constant number? Zero, One, Pi, Euler’s Constant, the Imaginary Number? Constant of permittivity or permeability? Something else?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2018/01/the-infamous-liebster-award/math.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Handwritten Latin and Greek alphabets&quot; title=&quot;My handwriting? Ha. I wish...&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;My handwriting? Ha. I wish...&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Describe the last experience that made you laugh without those around you finding it amusing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Describe the last experience where everyone else found something hilarious that you didn’t understand.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;From now on, you are only allowed to listen to one genre of music. Which genre do you choose?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Which conspiracy theory do you most want/hope to be true? Why?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set a timer for four hours from now (or whenever you are not working on the blog post you are currently writing). When the timer rings, immediately paste the contents of your computer’s clipboard, save them, and explain their context as the answer to this final question.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nominations&quot;&gt;Nominations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;aka-the-plot-twist&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;a.k.a. The Plot Twist&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having poured so much effort into this blog so far, I am ashamed to leave it incomplete due to a single negative perspective found on the Internet. However, as a matter of respect for other content producers and young professionals trying to establish a personal brand online, I have decided not to distribute any nominations for the Liebster award.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why did I make this decision?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon attempting to find eleven blogs with under two hundred followers (as the rules specify), I stumbled upon &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.forums.wordpress.com/topic/for-liebster-awards-how-do-i-find-out-how-many-followers-a-blog-has?replies=5&quot;&gt;this conversation&lt;/a&gt; that condemned “blog awards” as amateurish attempts to artificially raise SEO rankings. Even blogs with valuable and unique content can have their reputation undermined by getting caught up in chain-based blog awards. Regardless of one’s intention in posting, partaking in such activities gives the appearance of one floundering for quality material.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will still publish this post as it is, because I respect the person who awarded me the Liebster and wish to support her in her first steps into blogging. However, I do not want to put anyone else under duress by publicly pressuring them to publish content that they do not feel is consistent with their online persona or professional image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(As an aside, I am well aware of the irony of my decision, given that my blog likely has under 10 readers and is far from “public pressure”!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said, I encourage anyone reading this blog who feels comfortable responding to the aforementioned questions–whether by commenting, blogging, posting on social media, or even shooting me an email–to take a chance and codify your thoughts! Sharing our lives with others through written language is a stimulating challenge and a wonderful blessing from God, and if nothing else I hope that this discursive draft has inspired a few others to transform thoughts into words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Ecclesiastes 3:1. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Neill Robson</name></author><category term="blogging" /><category term="personal" /><category term="family" /><summary type="html">As an encouragement to continue sharing my thoughts and experiences online, a person near and dear to my heart nominated me for the Liebster Award.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Access vs. Ownership</title><link href="https://neillrobson.com/blog/2017/05/29/access-versus-ownership/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Access vs. Ownership" /><published>2017-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://neillrobson.com/blog/2017/05/29/access-versus-ownership</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://neillrobson.com/blog/2017/05/29/access-versus-ownership/">&lt;p&gt;Recently I came across advertising online for a new co-living experiment taking
place in Los Angeles. The name of the startup is PodShare. Essentially, the goal
is to provide customers with location-independent access to a minimal set of
resources necessary to live and work effectively in an urban environment. &lt;!--more--&gt; A bunk
on a wooden frame, a charging station, and a chalkboard identifying the
inhabitant are included in the package; doors, locks, and curtains are not.
Aside from the bed itself, all areas within a PodShare location are public: the
refrigerator and cooking utilities are shared, workspaces are common, and the
restrooms are handled dormitory-style. Maintaining a clean and safe environment
is as much the residents’ job as it is the staff’s, in the sense that everyone’s
space can be seen from all angles, creating an aura of community watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017/05/access-vs-ownership/clean-pods.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;PodShare bunk beds&quot; title=&quot;A typical quiet afternoon amongst the pods&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;A typical quiet afternoon amongst the pods&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this description is hard to visualize, a good video providing an overview and
history of the startup can be found
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=H_ILu-R-Nz8&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-bare-luxuries&quot;&gt;The Bare Luxuries&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My initial reaction to this foreign living concept could be described best as a
shameful terror. Terror, because I couldn’t imagine living in a situation so
hostile to privacy and ownership of space. Shame, because in the culture that is
starting this movement towards “Housing as a Service,” I recognize values and
visions that I myself hold dear. Would rejecting this development make me a
hypocrite?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In truth, the initiative of PodShare makes several steps toward a lifestyle that
I have learned to esteem. To enjoy a content and fulfilling life in such an
environment, you can’t have too much baggage: there aren’t many nooks large
enough for one to unload their extra belongings, and there aren’t many ears
patient enough for one to unload their ponderous past. “Podestrians,” as they
are called, must minimize their possessions to the bare necessities. Wherever
one life is lacking, another life is prepared and encouraged to fill the gap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The environmental benefits are also considerable. The most bare-bones apartment
complex that could accommodate the same number of men and women would require at
least three times the land area and an order of magnitude more capital
resources, not to mention the marginal costs and inefficiencies associated with
independent thermostats, water lines, and electric service. Furthermore,
splitting the community into individual &lt;em&gt;houses&lt;/em&gt; would practically necessitate
the construction of a new subdivision: an impossibility in any principally urban
environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking the idea to an even larger scale, PodShare claims that if it were to
expand its influence far enough, one would no longer need to book a hotel when
travelling. After all, a bed in one location is a bed in &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; location with a
vacancy–just check out of your hometown PodShare and catch a bus to your new
location! How inconceivable that freedom is to the modern American citizen: the
concept that moving across the country for a week, month, or indefinitely could
be as simple as packing some carry-ons and catching a flight. Realtors,
mortgages, and moving vans need not apply. Sell your house, and ditch that
timeshare too: &lt;strong&gt;your bed &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; your timeshare now.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ownerships-intrinsic-value&quot;&gt;Ownership’s Intrinsic Value&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PodShare challenges our very definitions of house and home. “The future is
access, not ownership,” claims Elvina Beck, the founder of the company.
Millennials invest in gym memberships, public transportation, and music
streaming services rather than purchasing the physical capital necessary to
enjoy these luxuries for ourselves. Why not extend that idea to our very homes?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017/05/access-vs-ownership/community.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Elvina Beck&quot; title=&quot;The occasional evening activity creates a sense of community. Hopefully nobody was looking to sleep tonight.&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;The occasional evening activity creates a sense of community. Hopefully nobody was looking to sleep tonight.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do agree that, in the general case, owning less can lead to living more. Our
culture in the United States has lost much of that compassionate, cooperative
nature that first brought society together when individuals would have failed
living alone. To put less reliance on the grasp of one’s own two hands, and
instead seek to be a strength in others’ weaknesses as they likewise provide
what you may lack, fills one’s soul in a beautiful and irreplaceable manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But to what extent must we deny our own desire for control over physical
possessions to reap the intangible benefits of a cooperative lifestyle? Are
there not memories, emotions, and even fragments of our identity engrained in
our living spaces that could not exist without a sense of locality, of
ownership?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Motivational speaker &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.simplybenglenn.com/&quot;&gt;Ben Glenn&lt;/a&gt; offers a
powerful example of this concept. To this day, I can recall with vivid detail
the Spring evening in 2009 when I witnessed him transform a black canvas into an
breathtaking explosion of variegated color before our eyes. The audience
journeyed with him step by step through the discovery process of artistic
creation, and by the end of the experience we all felt as though we, too, owned
the final work. Watching Ben share the exact same message at a different venue
or via a different medium holds none of the same gravity for me, because my
ownership and identity is contained in that one particular event, time, and
place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would I be satisfied if, rather than attending that 2009 conference, I simply
received a recording of the event, to be viewed on demand at any location or
time? More importantly, if I had never experienced the original, &lt;em&gt;would I even
know what I was missing from the experience?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017/05/access-vs-ownership/ben-glenn.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ben Glenn&quot; title=&quot;Ben may create the same drawing thousands of times, but the one he crafted when I was in attendance was uniquely mine. No recreation does it justice.&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Ben may create the same drawing thousands of times, but the one he crafted when I was in attendance was uniquely mine. No recreation does it justice.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do not believe I could describe with any accuracy the psychological difference
between owning a home and having geographically-independent access to shelter,
but I can only imagine that the effect would be similar to replacing such an
intimate artistic experience with a recording. Though the instrumental value of
housing has been demonstrated to be extractable into an on-demand construct, the
spirit of home feels tied intrinsically to geography. Stripping ourselves of
that luxury may not leave us physically homeless, but surely impoverished in
spirit. As Yi-Fu Tuan would perhaps characterize the change, we would be
accumulating the freedom of &lt;em&gt;space&lt;/em&gt; at the expense of the identity and security of
&lt;em&gt;place&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-divine-model&quot;&gt;A Divine Model&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For much of His ministry on earth, Jesus was truly homeless. “Foxes have dens
and birds of the sky have nests, but the Son of Man has no place to lay His
head,” Jesus stated in response to a scribe’s possibly naive proclamation of
devotion.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Were His disciples willing to give up not only the physical comforts
of shelter, but the very identity tied to their earthly homes, in order to
accept adoption into God’s kingdom by Christ’s sacrifice? In what capacity is my
worldly identity preventing me from perceiving the transformation that God so
desires to work in His child and slave?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And on a deeper inspection of Christ’s life, giving up house did not mean giving
up home. His ties to his earthly family were not lost: rather, He found His
family multiplied to all who followed the will of His Father.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; He shared
meals with brothers in the houses of the rich and poor, in the city and on the
beach, with intimacy and with thousands. He invested none of His identity in an
earthly dwelling, and yet He has arguably produced the greatest impact on
history and society that any individual has ever effected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not ashamed to admit that, given my upbringing and human nature, the idea of
housing as evanescent “access” in contrast to home ownership scares me. But
looking at the life of my King, as well as the consequences of our past and our
hopes for the future, I believe that this physical and cultural transformation
may have the potential for great salutary good, should we give it the proper
thought and introspection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…And let’s be honest, PodShare has no plans for global domination by any
extent: they still receive most of their business from millennial vagabonds and
summer camps. We have ample time to reflect and discuss!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are your thoughts on this housing movement? Let me know in the comments
below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;For a fascinating and edifying discussion on this topic, see Tuan’s work
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.upress.umn.edu/book-division/books/space-and-place&quot;&gt;Space and Place&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Matthew 8:20, HCSB &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Matthew 12:49-50 &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Neill Robson</name></author><category term="personal" /><category term="lifestyle" /><summary type="html">Recently I came across advertising online for a new co-living experiment taking place in Los Angeles. The name of the startup is PodShare. Essentially, the goal is to provide customers with location-independent access to a minimal set of resources necessary to live and work effectively in an urban environment.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Tea</title><link href="https://neillrobson.com/blog/2016/06/15/the-tea/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Tea" /><published>2016-06-15T08:16:38+00:00</published><updated>2016-06-15T08:16:38+00:00</updated><id>https://neillrobson.com/blog/2016/06/15/the-tea</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://neillrobson.com/blog/2016/06/15/the-tea/">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When in China, drink like the Chinese drink.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s the goal, and the beverage of choice over here is, as you probably know, tea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tea is one aspect of Chinese culture that cannot be exaggerated by even the most embarrassingly inaccurate caricatures. It truly is everywhere: tea is served at nearly every restaurant and cafeteria you enter, you receive boiling water and teabags every morning in your dorm room, and you’ll more often see thermoses than water bottles in people’s hands on the street. Honestly, the unofficial adoption of tea as the national drink of China is (in my humble opinion) an excellent decision. After all, while tap water is risky and alcohol doesn’t quench one’s thirst, boiling water is bacteria-free, offers no health risks (other than burning oneself, of course) and, on the contrary, is allegedly healthier to drink than cold beverages! Furthermore, tea comes in so many forms and varieties (from the medicinal stuff to the nasty wannabe Starbucks knockoffs) that, like wine, one will never run out of new varieties and subtleties to discover.  The wine analogy is accurate on a cultural level, too, insofar as China’s attitude toward tea mirrors the wine aficionados of the West.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my time here in China, I had the wonderful opportunity to visit both a tea museum and tea plantation. And of all the experiences I’ve had, I do believe that nowhere was the culture shock more pronounced than in experiencing China’s devotion to tea. There aren’t as many pictures in this post as usual (for reasons you will shortly understand), but hopefully the narratives I’m coming home with will do at least some justice to the experience! I’ll try a slightly different post format this time, where the story will go along independently of the images, which will have separate captions describing them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any case, without further ado…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-plantation&quot;&gt;The Plantation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most famous tea in China is without a doubt Longjing (龙井: “dragon well”) green tea. The only place in the world that it is grown is in the rural villages around West Lake in the city of Hangzhou, Zhejiang, China. Tea labeled “Longjing” from any other location (Sichuan, Yunan, etc.) is considered fake. Hangzhou takes their status as the sole producer of authentic Longjing tea very seriously; to visit one of these fabled tea plantations to get firsthand experience of the substance is only natural for any tourist in the area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160608_161804_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rolling hills of tea bushes&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The rolling hills of tea bushes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the bus drove into the countryside, several relatively large houses slid past our view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Tea farmers,” explained our tour guide, “is one of most rich people in China. Actually only some business men more money than Longjing farmers.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How much do they sell this stuff for?&lt;/em&gt; I wondered. &lt;em&gt;In restaurants, tea seems to be too cheap to charge for!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, how ignorant I was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arriving at the location where we were to be given a tour of the farming and processing procedures, we stepped off the bus into a humid gray day and meandered over to the nearest Longjing tea bush. They weren’t by any means in short supply; these bushes were about chest high on average and lined every hill and valley we drove through. Seeing the luscious, deep green leaves on the bush we were examining, I wondered why this one hadn’t yet been stripped clean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160603_150529.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tourists picking tea leaves&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Tourists love to pretend that they know how to pick tea leaves.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Actually this one already harvested by farmers,” our guide corrected us. “Good quality Longjing tea, only sprout leaves used, maybe one or two on a twig.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were shown a recently harvested leaf and realized that they were hardly more than sprouts. Leaves any longer than your pinky toe were already too mature, and would be left on the bush until the next season. The ideal Longjing tea leaves, the guide informed us, should look like a small bird’s tongue protruding from its mouth. Me being the pragmatic guy I am, I naturally assumed that this was just a bunch of snobbish talk. However, further research revealed that such picky harvests are in fact vital to creating a tea with the proper chemical balance: extended exposure to the elements produces oxidation which ruins many of the precious nutrients within the leaves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally, to pick just the sprouting leaves on an individual or two-by-two basis, no machines are suitable for the task: only hand-picking will do the trick. There are three harvest times–one in Spring, Summer, and Autumn–and each harvest is supposedly of a “lower quality” than the previous one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Okay,&lt;/em&gt; I thought, &lt;em&gt;that imposes a bit of a limit on how much of this stuff is actually produced. How many kilograms of tea are harvested per bush?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That answer depends on when during processing you are measuring the weight. Harvested leaves must be dry-fired in a large iron pan almost immediately upon separation from their host bush, so as to avoid the dreaded effects of oxidation. The first firing evaporates external moisture, and the second firing yields leaves in their final, dry (but not yet shriveled), sterile state. To avoid defacing the bird-tongue-like beauty of these little Longjing sprouts, the firing process must also be done by hand. I do not exaggerate when I say that these tea farmers stick bare palms into pans of roasting iron and spread the tea leaves around the bottom without so much as a blister appearing on their own fingers. Either those farmers’ hands are made of rubber, or those Longjing tea leaves should be used as insulation in fire-safe buildings. Holy cow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, the amount of tea per bush? Let’s just say it’s not measured in kilos, but in &lt;em&gt;grams&lt;/em&gt;. And we were standing in the only plantation officially recognized by China as producing this product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and by the way, 1.3 billion people want to buy this stuff. So it’s pretty valuable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-demonstration&quot;&gt;The Demonstration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After strolling around the plantation for a little while, we were escorted into a small building with simple, traditional Chinese architecture, and then through some sliding doors into what looks like a conference room. A long oval table stretches the length of the room, and on one end are situated several dozen bound paper packages and green cans. The group is seated and everyone is given an empty glass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A smartly-dressed young woman enters the room and closes the doors behind her. Taking her place at the head of the conference table with the packages and cans, she proceeds to explain to the group where and how Longjing tea is enjoyed. At the same time, her hands, moving seemingly independent of her mind, begin unwrapping one of the packages and depositing a pinch of the contents into each of our glasses. Boiling water is added, and the Longjing tea in front of each of us begins to steep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160603_154723.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A kettle of purple Yixing clay&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The taste profile of Longjing tea is supposedly diminished if the beverage is not first steeped in a kettle of purple Yixing clay.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typically, the highest quality Longjing tea (the first pickings) are reserved specifically for government officials and for gifts distributed by Chinese foreign ambassadors. The little that remains is often auctioned off, yielding prices up to thousands of US dollars for a single gram (hardly enough to make a single glass). Because of its value, a person typically re-uses the same tea leaves in a given glass or thermos for an entire working day, refilling it with boiling water whenever necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Okay, time to begin appreciating Longjing tea,” announces our lecturer. We raise the glasses to our lips, but she scolds us and tells us first to swirl the tea in our glasses and then inhale the steam. …So this stuff really &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; supposed to be consumed like wine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, we’ve sniffed it and it smells like collard greens. Now we flex our lips in preparation to consume the liquid and–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Stop, you first need to look at Longjing tea. Hold glass like this and open wide eyes.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She cups her hand over the glass and directs the steam from the cup into her left eye. Reluctantly, we all follow suit, and switch eyes on her command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This cures cataract,” explained our guide. “After look at computer for all day, you should look at Longjing tea instead.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, now it’s definitely time to start drinking it. After blowing the leaves out of the way, we take some tiny sips of the scalding hot liquid and, well, it tastes pretty good! “Collard greens” is still the first thought that comes to my mind, but that isn’t to say that the gustatory experience was unsatisfactory–on the contrary, I greatly enjoy collard greens, and I was perfectly fine drinking collard green broth if that’s what they do here in China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160603_154144.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A teacup of pure white jade&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;If you don’t consume tea from a glass of pure white jade, you’re obviously not worthy of it gracing your lips.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Little did I know how much more this liquid was than simply “collard green broth.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we were sipping away, our lecturer was busy filling up a glass with her own mixture of substances, while talking away at a pace that would make Mr. Shamwow proud. Beginning with a healthy spoonful of rice, she explained that she was mixing together a scaled-down chemical equivalent of a person’s typical daily diet. She proceeded to add various oils and syrups, ranging from soy sauce to peanut oil to lard to molasses, and mixed the glass’s contents together into a brown mush.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Some are people who drink water cleanse out diet,” she informed us as she poured a glass of water into the mush and swirled it around. “But not very effective.” The water was poured out again, much more turbid after the treatment, but leaving just as much mush in the original glass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Now we try same thing, but with Longjing tea.” She poured more water into the glass, then produced a small pill from one of the boxes on the table. “This same as ten cup of Longjing tea. You can also buy here and take, like vitamin.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Into the glass the pill was thrown, and the mixture was carefully swirled once more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Now we empty again.” The disposal container received the second batch of dirty water–this time pitch black as it was poured away. A collective gasp went up from those who looked into the original glass of mush.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All that remained were fresh, white grains of rice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So you see, very good for body!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-sale&quot;&gt;The Sale&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I don’t actually know how healthy it is to be drinking a liquid that is capable of extracting any visible presence of salt, sugar, and fat from one’s intestines. On the other hand, we just witnessed what seemed like pure witchcraft, and not one of us could claim to be left unaffected by the dramatic performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160603_154323.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;An opulent tea room&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;How I imagine the Count of Monte Cristo’s tea room is decorated.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our presenter, seeing our wide eyes and gaping mouths, knew it was time to make her strike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An assistant was called in and the two women began throwing open the brown paper packages, revealing every shade of green Longjing leaves imaginable. The now mystical scent of collard greens filled the locked, windowless conference room. The orchestrator of the presentation slipped on a pair of skin-tight white gloves and picked up one of the green canisters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The leaves still fresh from roasting, not packaged for you yet,” we were informed, as the lid of the canister was popped off by those anonymous gloved hands and the empty, stainless inside was presented to the audience. “We package here for you now.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A white glove dove into the mounds of Longjing leaves and pulled out a few handfuls, depositing them one by one into the canister until tea was piled to the top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This look full, but be assured,” warned our saleswoman, with rising urgency, “some settlement may occur.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Placing a gloved hand over the top of the can, she bashed the bottom of the can into the table several times. While the sound was still ringing in our ears the hand was removed, revealing a can only two-thirds full.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Is why we pack here, so you see we pack actually very full.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again and again she scooped up tea leaves, packing them into the can with force that must have rivaled the vacuum bags some of us used to bring our clothes to China. The lid was finally crammed onto the top, and the can was passed to the assistant who mechanically sealed it closed and rested it upon her hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So you see, very full. If you doubt, please pack yourself.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other products were set out on display before us, from Longjing tea cakes to the ultra-concentrated colon-cleansing pills that sterilized the rice. After everything had been presented and positioned with care, the statement that everyone had been waiting for was uttered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You not barter here, we set fix price. For high-quality Longjing tea, one canister, regular price 600 yuan. We give to you half price, 300 yuan. You may pay RMB, USD, or the credit card.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all began to cast sidelong glances at each other as we shuffled through our wallets. This stuff obviously wasn’t the “first picking” seen at auctions–the price was too unbelievably low for that–but nonetheless, we had just seen with our eyes and tasted with our tongues the substance that was now being packaged before us, so we had little excuse to object to the trade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160603_164655.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Compressed tea cakes&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Compressed tea cakes, with price tags running around $240-250.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Large stacks of bills started trading hands. As I watched my peers, my only thought was how illicit this whole process seemed to be: sitting around a conference table in a locked room with no decor, hungrily observing gloved hands pack mysterious dried leaves into sealed canisters to be passed along to a customer for a large sum. When we were finally released into the open air again, hardly anybody carried their purchases in their bare hands: the vast majority left these goods tucked away with care in the bottom of a purse or backpack. Some people could be observed absentmindedly tapping their bags occasionally to reassure themselves that their purchase had not left them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I only hope that we are not caught in customs returning home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s the story of my experience with the culture of tea in China. Needless to say, the process left quite a significant impression on me, and I definitely believe that, regardless of its mystical and prodigious alleged properties, it will take a much more extensive role in my diet back home in the United States!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160603_151658.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Historic tea garden advertisement&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Hongchow’s Mur Kee Tea Gardens: drinks so good, they’ll make you wanna slap yo’ momma.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, I’ve located green tea popsicles, green tea toothpaste, and green tea ice cream here in China. There’s no doubt that I’ll be paying premium to get my hands on the stuff back home. Say goodbye to my poor wallet…&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>neill</name></author><category term="china" /><category term="travel" /><category term="food" /><category term="personal" /><summary type="html">When in China, drink like the Chinese drink. That’s the goal, and the beverage of choice over here is, as you probably know, tea.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Environment</title><link href="https://neillrobson.com/blog/2016/06/09/the-environment/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Environment" /><published>2016-06-09T10:03:11+00:00</published><updated>2016-06-09T10:03:11+00:00</updated><id>https://neillrobson.com/blog/2016/06/09/the-environment</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://neillrobson.com/blog/2016/06/09/the-environment/">&lt;p&gt;So many of my experiences in Hangzhou are relatively small excursions: individually, they aren’t worth an entire blog post, but they amount to quite a bit when added up! At the same time, a “Miscellaneous” blog post should honestly be saved for the end of a trip, so I’ll try my best to theme this one as more nature-related. &lt;!--more--&gt; Indeed, the vast majority of Hangzhou’s attractions are outdoors–a characteristic that I greatly admire!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160514_145419.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;house of courtyards&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Near the beginning of our trip we visited a Chinese mansion exhibiting some of the older architectural styles of China. The Chinese culture of the time took an incredible amount of liberties with indoor/outdoor spaces to create an astonishingly beautiful effect. Areas such as the ones pictured above and below were entirely “inside” the house, and doors could just as easily lead to artificial caves as they could lead to “rooms” as we think of them in the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160514_151809.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;stone path over river&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160514_155700.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;floor plan&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Above is a floor plan of the house. As you can see, most places are naturally exposed to the elements, and roofs only exist over the edges of major rooms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160514_144930.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;kitchen&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, your modern American “dream kitchen” can’t shake a stick at the massive size of the facilities in this bachelor’s place. There are full ovens on both sides of that marble counter on the right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160514_144733.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;bonsai&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yeah, they also grew bonsai trees to obnoxiously large sizes. (Thanks to Michael for posing next to this one, for scale!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160518_102120.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;lilypad landscape&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hangzhou is also known for its enormous and beautiful botanical gardens, of which I took quite a few photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160518_102801.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;fake deer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although they may be known for their flowers, the botanical gardens certainly aren’t known for their wildlife!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160518_102527.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;boat&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160518_104013.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;circle door&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doors are always a favorite posing spot for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160518_105418-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;lake, no lilies&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160518_111110.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;rock garden&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you can’t grow flowers, you can always fall back on your splendid rock collection!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160522_152556-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;distant pagoda&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also went out to quite a few temples and pagodas–some more accessible than others. We found that when it comes to trails, the Chinese have very low tolerance for handicap-accessibility or even general safety measures. Most of the time, the only precaution taken would be a sign such as the one below, ordering people not to climb. We can see how well that went:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160522_152915.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;don't climb&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people in our group were a bit more adventurous than I upon these rocks; at first I thought it was because they couldn’t read the warnings in Chinese, but I was quickly put in my place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160522_154755.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;cherished life&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Thanks for the photo op, Patrick!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160522_154447_PN.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;xihu panorama&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But climbing, of course, is where all the best views are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160522_154502.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Eischen climbing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And when your professors do it, it’s hard to overcome the social pressure, you know?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160525_140325.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;stairs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, the climbing trouble doesn’t end when you get to the pagoda…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160525_141904.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;doorway&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;especially not for tall guys like me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160525_140852_LL.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;roofing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the fabulously decorated walls and roofs encourage you as you cross the threshold of the 72nd floor on your way to the 134th…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160525_141125_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;power lines&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, you are occasionally greeted with power lines or some other unfortunate presence in an otherwise serene environment, but I actually found the vast scale that they imply to be quite photogenic!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160525_141817.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;tiny farm&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You take whatever sunlight you can get and make the most of it, you know?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160525_144035.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;tiny pagoda&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back on the ground floor of the place, I felt a lot taller than when I first arrived. I’m not sure if that’s the psychological effect of climbing the thing, or because…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160525_144430_BF.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;hand on the stairs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;..there were actually a ton of mini pagodas scattered around the big one!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160525_144124_BF.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;giant&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fun times being a giant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160525_145121_BF.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;elephant&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tried to use a selfie stick here, but I’m still too awkward with handling it. …Look at the expression on that elephant. He’s so judgmental! All like, “is this dude seriously using a selfie stick to take a photo with me? What a flippant, obnoxious foreigner! I would &lt;em&gt;never&lt;/em&gt; attempt the same thing with &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt; nose if I ever visited &lt;em&gt;his&lt;/em&gt; country! Sheesh, what an American.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160603_144337.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;snail and hand&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the US, when it rains, worms come out and cover the sidewalks. In China, the equivalent are the snails!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160604_072407_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;clear day picture&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just think of all the beautiful sunrises that the people in the US missed because they were busy watching the sunset over there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160526_165525_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;foggy day picture&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s just as beautiful on a foggy day too–don’t get me wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, that’s all for this blog! The next post will hopefully feature a pharmacy, tea museum, and underground bunker. See you next time!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>neill</name></author><category term="china" /><category term="travel" /><category term="personal" /><category term="nature" /><summary type="html">So many of my experiences in Hangzhou are relatively small excursions: individually, they aren’t worth an entire blog post, but they amount to quite a bit when added up! At the same time, a “Miscellaneous” blog post should honestly be saved for the end of a trip, so I’ll try my best to theme this one as more nature-related.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Food</title><link href="https://neillrobson.com/blog/2016/06/02/the-food/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Food" /><published>2016-06-02T13:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-06-02T13:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://neillrobson.com/blog/2016/06/02/the-food</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://neillrobson.com/blog/2016/06/02/the-food/">&lt;p&gt;There’s one big problem with food in China: more often than not, when you try to photograph it, it’s already escaped you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t worry–I’m not talking about the type of food that can run away from you on its own accord! (They do sell that kind of thing, but you won’t see any of it on this blog.) No, I’m instead referring to the unique and wonderful way that food is &lt;em&gt;served&lt;/em&gt; to large groups in restaurants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than everybody getting their own dish of food, you are instead given a small empty plate and bowl with chopsticks and a spoon. All the food that everybody ordered is then presented in serving dishes on a lazy susan the middle of the table, and its up to you to grab what you want to eat before the dish is spun away from under your nose!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, you learn to use chopsticks quickly when your nourishment depends on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said, I’ve tried my best to compile a few images of the types of food I’ve consumed here in Hangzhou. The list is by no means comprehensive–and it will likely grow exponentially before I leave–but hopefully I will leave you with some idea of the wild and wonderful world that is authentic Chinese cuisine!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/05/P_20160525_080017.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;fruit&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160525_125002.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;tv dinner&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll start with the tame stuff. Right across the street from the dormitory is a nice little collection of convenience stores and food shops, selling everything from fruit to loaves of bread and dumplings. Usually my lunch consists of something similar to the above: a chopped-and-peeled dish of some mystery produce (dragonfruit, in this case–delicious, like a mild kiwi!), and a microwavable meal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, before you get on my case about eating frozen food like a typical American tourist, hear me out! These things are &lt;em&gt;nothing&lt;/em&gt; like the cheap Hot Pockets sold in the United States. They often have balanced amounts of vegetables and grains, with a variety of meat or vegetarian options that are easily recognizable. Furthermore, when you buy it at the c-store, they heat it up for you and provide chopsticks and a toothpick at no extra charge!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, not to brag or anything, but the entire lunch pictured above costs around $3.00 (yes, that’s US dollars). Talk about living on a budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160531_074016.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;breakfast&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of living on a budget, the cafeteria breakfasts literally only cost dimes here. If you’re super hungry in the mornings (like me) and need to order noodles, an egg, three sticky buns, and a warm glass of soy milk, it will put you out around a dollar fifty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trust me, if Chinese people are considered relatively slim, it has &lt;em&gt;nothing&lt;/em&gt; to do with the price of the food here!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160526_183411.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;lazy susan&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting with this image one can see a sampling of the food collection served at a typical large lazy-susan dinner. The blessing and the curse of this service style is that you almost never see the same dish twice. All too often I eat something absolutely heavenly, but by the time I look up the dish is gone and I never see it again in the future. &lt;em&gt;sigh!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160526_183030.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;meat over lettuce&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add to the stress of the Chinese food wheel of fortune, often dishes such as this pork is served over a garnish of fresh leafy greens. Pretty indeed, but “fresh leafy greens” is synonymous for “unwashed bacteria farm” in China, so nothing touching the garnish is safe to eat. You’d better level that mountain like a borderline-bankrupt coal miner if you want any meat, because once you get to the base no one is touching those pieces at the bottom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160526_183414.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;tofu&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tofu. Escaping the iron grip of chopstick masters since 2000BC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160526_183417.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;pineapple chicken&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pineapple chicken! One quickly learns that China doesn’t get its share of fruits and veggies as separate dishes: you’ve got to sleuth them out of the meals labeled as “Three-Bird Plus Beef Wrapped in Tofu Supreme.” Fortunately, with dishes such as this one, it isn’t hard to find the fruit!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160526_183528.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ice-cream bread&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So basically, this is a loaf of hot bread chopped into cubes on the inside, with a scoop of ice cream dumped on top. You use your chopsticks to dig a cube out of the melting sugar magma seeping into the carbohydrate volcano, dip it into the cream on top for extra calories, consume your piece of the destruction, and repeat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have no idea why this isn’t a thing in the United States!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160526_183531.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;mushrooms and cheese substitute&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we have a mushroom casserole. There are so many mushrooms in China, I’m astonished that there hasn’t been an influx of Italian plumbers… But actually, I photographed this dish to talk about the cheese. As it turns out, cheese is virtually unknown in China–even in the pizza shops–and instead they use various forms of dairy-free cheese substitute. Surprisingly, despite their bad reputation in the US, dairy-free cheeses in Chinese dishes actually complement the local tastes quite well! I would even venture to consider the culinary experience as something altogether unique from cheese, and pretty good too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160526_183651.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;eggplant&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eggplant is served here the way it should be everywhere: in a boiling hot sauce of Sichuan peppers. Unfortunately I don’t have an image of the “dancing” eggplant variety, where bonito flakes are added and propelled into the air by the radiation, but I’ll leave finding pictures of that dish as an exercise to the reader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also featured in the above image are fish-sticks–Americans love them some fish sticks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160526_184141.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;fish #1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here comes the fish;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160526_184727.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;fish #2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drowned in his dish!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160526_184734.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hot greens&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t worry, there are a few dishes that contain your average, boiled-to-death cabbage to add some semblance of leafy greens to your diet. Other greens not pictured here are bamboo shoots and boiled okra: the seeds work wonders for sweeping out one’s digestive system!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160526_182147.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;tea cakes&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, one of the dishes that I can always look forward to at any self-respecting Chinese restaurant is the tea cake. These little patties are covered in sesame seeds and filled with green-tea flavored sweet bean paste, and in my opinion are a thousand times more delicious than any ice cream volcano loaf. Close runner-ups are pumpkin fries and sweet mung bean paste (you can tell I’ve been doing a great job at remembering my Chinese food names). The latter is a miracle-worker when you’ve put your money where your mouth is with some fancy-looking Sichuan firecracker and now the mouth in question is purple and numb with pain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only two more food pictures remain, and a quick word of caution along with it: Japanese food in China is just as expensive as Japanese food in America. Furthermore, it consists almost exclusively of raw fish and fresh leafy vegetables. This particular Japanese place I went to, upon sitting our group down, explained to us that they had just opened and that every dish was 25% off because they were still “testing out” the recipes with customers. Oh boy. I just lost all confidence in this institution. While the rest of the group proceeded to order several plates of sushi and a boatload of mystery meat:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160527_182126.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;sushi boat&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…my wise-stomached friend and I turned instead to the kids menu and found the only cooked dishes in the entire restaurant: fried rice and ramen noodles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/06/P_20160527_181612.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;fried rice&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hooray for defensive eating!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>neill</name></author><category term="china" /><category term="travel" /><category term="food" /><category term="personal" /><summary type="html">There’s one big problem with food in China: more often than not, when you try to photograph it, it’s already escaped you.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Climb</title><link href="https://neillrobson.com/blog/2016/05/24/the-climb/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Climb" /><published>2016-05-24T09:07:03+00:00</published><updated>2016-05-24T09:07:03+00:00</updated><id>https://neillrobson.com/blog/2016/05/24/the-climb</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://neillrobson.com/blog/2016/05/24/the-climb/">&lt;p&gt;For just about every weekday morning here in China, I wake up around 6:00 and, after some morning prayer, I set off across campus to a little mountain trail called “The 1000 Steps” for some exercise. &lt;!--more--&gt; To be honest, I couldn’t have possibly asked for a better way to start off every day here in Hangzhou: to stay active and healthy despite living in the middle of one of China’s larger cities is quite a blessing indeed! The following images are just a sampling of the morning routine I’ve adopted:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/05/P_20160522_125345.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Campus road&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ~5 minute walk I take through campus to the trail. With all of the trees and grass, walking through Zhejiang University’s Yuquan campus feels just like home in Raleigh!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/05/P_20160523_064705.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bike parking&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…Well, except for one small thing: the parking situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Hey, let’s all park our bikes in a calm and orderly fashion. &lt;cite&gt;Nobody, ever, in China&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/05/P_20160522_125020.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Entering the neighborhood&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right behind campus is a side street leading to a tiny neighborhood, at the back of which is an entrance to the trail. Oftentimes the people living here will walk up to the top of the mountain to have a picnic breakfast or lunch while listening to radio news and talking with their neighbors. It’s a nice environment!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/05/P_20160522_124842.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Exiting the neighborhood&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A picture from the other direction, now looking towards the campus (which is not visible in this shot). Simply pivoting on my feet to the right leads me to…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/05/P_20160522_115034.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The entrance&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh boy. It’s about to get serious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-1000-steps&quot;&gt;The 1000 Steps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, it’s about 700, according to the numbers carved onto the steps. I suppose if one wanders all around the mountaintop, the approximate equivalent is 1000 steps, but your primary exertion will occur during this initial ascent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/05/P_20160522_115049.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The beginning&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It starts out rather slow, sort of like a warm-up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/05/P_20160522_115233.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The ascent&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the first 100 steps or so, the steps quickly narrow down to escalator size, exhibiting none of the American architectural luxury of switchbacks. Up we go!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/05/P_20160522_115401.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No. &lt;strong&gt;This is SPARTA!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/05/P_20160522_124330.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Side path&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of people ditch the stair route for a slightly more gradual dirt path, but as tempting as it looks, you’ll also find no shortage of mosquitoes and other blood-sucking parasites that way. Trust me, your sore feet are more than compensated by your smooth, unbruised legs when taking the steps!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/05/P_20160522_120111.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By this point pretty much everyone is completely winded, and you’re absolutely dying for a rest. Fortunately, right up ahead there’s a lovely little pool of standing water with an orange bucket perfect for scooping up some lukewarm, gray-green thirst-quenching drink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/05/P_20160522_123939.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Water break&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(The sign displays the following insightful comment: “This lid is broken; restoration is underway. We advise your safety.”)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/05/P_20160522_120303.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Skyline #1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you climb up this high, the skyline is utterly beautiful. Almost every day I come up here, I notice a different angle or perspective of the city that leaves me utterly breathless. (Or that might just be my exhaustion after the stair-climbing. I don’t know.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/05/P_20160522_123346_PN.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Skyline panorama&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/05/P_20160522_120508.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pavilion&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only a few more stairs to the top! As I mentioned, up here you’ll find people doing every manner of things, from listening to the news to eating snacks to just socializing. Some, like me, are crazy enough to push their bodies to even higher levels of physical exertion on what I affectionately dub the “Chinese Monkey Bars”:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/05/P_20160522_120648.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pull-up bars&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They’re perfectly sturdy, I swear. You should see the size of some of the guys who do sets on these things. Pull-ups are a &lt;em&gt;big&lt;/em&gt; deal in this area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/05/P_20160522_122601.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Push-up bench&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, no workout would be complete without some push-ups as well. I usually do them inclined on this bench, simply because it’s cleaner and my arms are too exhausted for anything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/05/P_20160522_123742.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Going down&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way down again!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/05/P_20160522_124455.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Vertigo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, you’ve got to be careful going down these steps–no jogging allowed. Well, I mean, it &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; allowed, but only if you don’t value your front teeth (which you’ll surely lose in the fall).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And with that, the journey is done! All said, I am exceedingly grateful for the presence of this wonderful public trail, and I know that it will be one of those memories which sticks with me long after I return home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One more picture, before signing off:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/05/P_20160522_125147.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;No riding&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Hmm, maybe it isn’t a good idea to ride bikes here. &lt;cite&gt;Nobody, ever, in China&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>neill</name></author><category term="china" /><category term="travel" /><category term="personal" /><category term="nature" /><summary type="html">For just about every weekday morning here in China, I wake up around 6:00 and, after some morning prayer, I set off across campus to a little mountain trail called “The 1000 Steps” for some exercise.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Room</title><link href="https://neillrobson.com/blog/2016/05/22/the-room/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Room" /><published>2016-05-22T11:42:13+00:00</published><updated>2016-05-22T11:42:13+00:00</updated><id>https://neillrobson.com/blog/2016/05/22/the-room</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://neillrobson.com/blog/2016/05/22/the-room/">&lt;p&gt;What does day-to-day life look like for an international student living at Zhejiang International University in Hangzhou? Many factors come into play, including food, physical activity, and social events–but it seemed appropriate to first introduce my dorm room: my “home away from home” so to speak. &lt;!--more--&gt; Those looking for vivid descriptions and tantalizing images of the exotic Hangzhou lifestyle may wish to wait for another post down the road. Even so, I cannot emphasize enough the importance of forming a bit of a safe haven when traveling abroad, in order to decompress after the day’s events, and Zhejiang University does a stellar job at providing such a location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, without further ado…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-bed-and-breakfast&quot;&gt;The Bed and Breakfast&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/05/P_20160515_172906.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Walking into the room&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here you can see the same perspective I have upon entering my room. You’ll notice that it’s a single-bed setup, with a dresser, desk, and television all provided. The view out the window is another dormitory, as you might expect. Unfortunately this image doesn’t capture the rainbow of color that appears when all the students hang their clothes to dry in the windows: it is in fact quite a beautiful sight in its own unique way!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/05/P_20160515_173000.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Walking out of the room&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My lovely shoes (which I dearly hope will not wear out before the end of this journey), as well as the doorway to my bathroom and the door to the hall. Yes, those little coat hangers have moose on them; just a little touch of home that the Zhejiang staff added to the room. (You think that’s special? Just wait for the description of the day-to-day room service.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/05/P_20160515_173017.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The bed&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike many of my peers, I am actually quite satisfied with the firmness of the bed. It is certainly more stiff than American standards (dropping a phone on the mattress yields a “klunk” noise), but since I am a back sleeper (not a side sleeper) I find it actually leaves me quite nimble getting up in the morning, rather than waking up sunken into an overly-soft mattress in some ergonomically abhorrent position. The pillow is softer than anything I’ve ever used at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sheets, as it turns out, are replaced daily by the cleaning service. Hold on, did you catch that? &lt;em&gt;Daily.&lt;/em&gt; We’re talking pillow and comforter as well: all of it is delivered fresh to the room every single day. If you happen to wander out back around four or five in the afternoon, you’ll see huge piles of the previous day’s sheets being loaded onto a truck for delivery to the washrooms. Don’t ask me why the cleaning policies are so pompous; in fact, I’ve only just begun describing the service here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/05/P_20160515_173048.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The breakfast&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll take a quick detour here to the pantry above my bed. My first trip to the convenience store (literally across the street from the dorm room) consisted mostly of these purchases. You can see “ten-grain bread” (which is actually white bread with ten grains sprinkled on the crust) and peanut butter and jelly: a delicious taste of home that seems to have no equivalent in typical Chinese cuisine. I also purchased some “Argentinian” raisins, which happen to be the size of golf balls and utterly mouth-watering (especially in hot cereal), as well as some powdered milk packets and high-fiber oatmeal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;But wait!&lt;/em&gt; I hear you cry. &lt;em&gt;How can you make oatmeal and milk if you can’t drink the water in China?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, you see, part of the room service includes a thermos of boiling hot water delivered fresh to your room every morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You ask a first-world question, you get a first-world answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/05/P_20160515_173235.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The hot water&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That blue thermos you see there is a miraculous piece of technology: I’ve left it sitting there overnight, and the water within it is still steaming hot the following morning. I swear, there are no plugs and no lids other than that foil-capped cork you see on top of it. Also included in our room service package are slippers (delivered fresh for every time the previous set have been used) and a teabag and glass (for your consumption pleasure). My orange water bottle is actually metal, which means I can pour hot water into it without it melting and let it cool overnight, but I’ve actually taken to buying five-liter jugs from the C-store so that I don’t forget the temperature of the metal and burn the skin off my palm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/05/P_20160515_173201-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The wardrobe&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My clothes, toiletries, laundry, and pharmacy. A woman on the bottom floor of the dorm directly behind ours offers a vertically-integrated laundry service for only around 20元 per load (~$3). You bring her a bag of dirty clothes, and 24 hours later they are washed, air-dried, folded and re-packaged for you to take back to your room. Sometimes when you walk into her shop, you can’t see the walls or floor due to the quantity of clothes all over the place. With all the rinse cycles running at once, sometimes you can’t hear her either. Being situated literally inside a college dormitory, I don’t think she’s running a risk of losing business anytime soon! I must get a picture of her shop uploaded here someday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/05/P_20160515_173443-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The bathroom entry&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t tell room service that I was standing on freshly-made sheets to take this masterpiece selfie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/05/P_20160515_173516.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The toiletries&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why, might you ask, do I have two sets of body wash and shampoo? Well, if they pick up your current set and detect that you’ve used it once (or maybe it leaked (or maybe there just wasn’t enough in that particular tube)) they give you another set, just in case. Also provided are fresh toothbrushes, toothpaste (herbal tea flavored–easily the best flavor I’ve ever had!), combs, and shower caps. The soap bottle in the bottom right was a c-store purchase that I use for washing out my tupperware bowl (featured above) along with boiling water. By the way, if I return home with no skin left on my hands, you’ll know why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/05/P_20160515_173527.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Towels&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Delivered fresh every morning. I hear that my peers have utilized (read: exploited) this service to chop open watermelons in their dorm rooms and wipe up the mess without fearing that their shower will smell like old fruit. I don’t blame them: the watermelon sold at the c-store next to campus is stellar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/05/P_20160515_173541-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Toilet&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two rolls of toilet paper, because I started to use the first roll. One morning when I first arrived I had clogged up the toilet due to my body adjusting to the new diet. That afternoon after class I planned to pick up a plunger form the c-store to fix the problem. However, when I returned to my dorm after my morning classes, I found that the cleaning staff had already unclogged the toilet for me. And left me a third roll of toilet paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t keep up with these guys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/05/P_20160515_173621-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The drain&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole bathroom is a shower, as can be seen by the sliding door and drain in this picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/05/P_20160515_173652.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Warning sign&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really tried hard to put on my best “duh” face here. When translated literally, this sign says “please slip with a small heart.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/05/P_20160515_173753.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Air unit&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/05/P_20160515_173819-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Remote&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Funny story: when I first arrived at the dorm, I couldn’t figure out how to work the air conditioning unit. No matter what buttons I pressed on the remote, the unit itself would give no perceptible response. Finally, I got so fed up that I just mashed every button at once and promptly went to bed. The next morning, I woke up in a pool of sweat. The unit was blowing out hot air. Checking the display on the remote, the current temperature was 30 degrees–Celsius. Fortunately, once the darn thing was actually blowing some kind of air out of it, jerry-rigging it to get cold air out wasn’t too big of a deal. And hey, one night in the Sahara isn’t too bad, you know?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, that’s all I have for now. In the near future I’ll hopefully document the food experience (trust me, there’s so much more than PB&amp;amp;J!), some of the areas in and around the campus, and maybe even a few more cultural excursions (to a pharmacy, of all places!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is Neill, signing off!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>neill</name></author><category term="china" /><category term="travel" /><category term="personal" /><summary type="html">What does day-to-day life look like for an international student living at Zhejiang International University in Hangzhou? Many factors come into play, including food, physical activity, and social events–but it seemed appropriate to first introduce my dorm room: my “home away from home” so to speak.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Middle Country</title><link href="https://neillrobson.com/blog/2016/05/19/the-middle-country/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Middle Country" /><published>2016-05-19T09:15:29+00:00</published><updated>2016-05-19T09:15:29+00:00</updated><id>https://neillrobson.com/blog/2016/05/19/the-middle-country</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://neillrobson.com/blog/2016/05/19/the-middle-country/">&lt;p&gt;Who would have guessed that one day I would be saying hello from China?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next few weeks, I’ll be doing my best to chronicle my journey through a Study Abroad experience in Hangzhou, across the world from my Raleigh hometown. &lt;!--more--&gt; As my first experience truly “out of the country,” it’s quite a giant leap from the comfortable North Carolina home I’m used to. But how much of the place we call our home floats beyond our consciousness until we are separated from it (and thereby made aware of it) by another way of life? That idea is what we put to the test when we embark on a journey such as this. As the famous Chinese-American geographer said,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;To identify wholly with the ambiance of a place is to lose the sense of its unique identity, which is revealed only when one can also see it from the outside. …The sense of place is perhaps never more acute than when one is homesick, and one can only be homesick when one is no longer at home. &lt;cite&gt;Yi-Fu Tuan&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-capital&quot;&gt;The Capital&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This journey begins in Beijing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If anybody ever tells you that “everything is bigger in Texas,” you can respond with confidence that “everything is bigg&lt;em&gt;est&lt;/em&gt; in Beijing.” Unfortunately, pictures truly cannot capture the prodigious nature of this city’s architecture and history, especially not when they are shot by an amateur such as myself, but one cannot pass through this home of over 20 million people without making a few attempts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/05/P_20160511_080002-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The airport&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The airport above covers over 3700 acres of land, roughly one-eighth the size of Raleigh. At 8:30pm on a Wednesday evening, it’s empty and quiet enough to hear the ghosts of the 2008 Olympic Games (for whom the airport was built) jostling their way into the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/05/P_20160512_085211.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tiananmen Square&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The city square is also the size of many, many football fields. Beijing, unlike American cities, does not boast its size in terms of height, but in terms of square area. Raleigh has one belt line; Beijing has six, with a seventh under construction. You can cross Raleigh in half an hour on a bad day; multiply that by five, and you might be on the other side of Beijing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/05/P_20160512_093954.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Forbidden Selfie&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point in the trip, I was still too self-conscious to take selfies (especially in a place called the “Forbidden City”), but selfie sticks are commonplace among the guests any major tourist attraction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/05/P_20160512_135151-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Great Wall parking lot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And of course you can’t go to China without conquering the Great Wall! The section we went to actually covered a circular area (rather than progressing in a line), because the surrounding mountains (and Mongols) necessitated a rather unique defense strategy. Our tour guide explained the military logic in detail, but in my opinion the real defense was the absurdly steep and uneven stairs with handrails only a foot above the ground. It was enough to make any enemy stumble, even if they did manage to scale to outside of the wall itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/05/P_20160512_141123_BF.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Great Wall selfie&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good exposure, bad finger positioning. I’ll get it at some point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/05/P_20160512_142857.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Beijing landscape&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re too far away here to really tell, but that entire “flat” area is all Beijing, with its apartments and skyscrapers. I was astonished by the incredibly large ratio of apartments to other buildings; they seemed like an invasive species of plant that crowded out all other buildings and industries. Dr. Griffin mentioned how the Chinese government was known for building “ghost cities,” in which apartment buildings and train stations are built in anticipation of population growth in a given area that doesn’t boom–or booms into a different location, leaving the new buildings empty. Even in Beijing itself, I often found myself wondering how all of those millions of people could possibly be productively employed, with so little physical evidence of businesses of any sort in the surrounding area. China has a lot of population problems on the horizon much more complex than simply hedging exponential growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/05/P_20160512_143704-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mountains&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just some pretty mountains. #desktop!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/05/P_20160512_143933.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Great wall circle&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here you can see the whole circular section of the great wall that we toured, viewed from the highest point. Off to the left you can see where it stretches off in a straight line once again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/05/P_20160513_092511.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Temple of Good Harvests&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t take many pictures at the Temple of Heaven in the places I should have. Much of the area was actually a park (with trees and flowers and grassy fields), where many people from the city came to play badminton or dance to music. Some people even came alone with their hackey-sacks and birdies and paddles, simply pulling people aside (even foreigners like us!) to play a game or two with them. When you live in such a vast concrete plain as Beijing, you really learn to cherish your parks and social areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016/05/P_20160513_094000.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Altar gate&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pathways like this were called “dragon lines,” upon which only the emperor was allowed to travel between his various facilities. Fun fact: when you’re the emperor and servants carry you everywhere, sometimes you get halfway to where you need to go before realizing that you forgot to change out of your pajamas. In that case, a dressing room is located conveniently halfway down the line for you to take a pit stop at, with the added benefit of giving your servants’ shoulders a much-needed break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s all the images I have from Beijing. This leg of the trip was mostly touristy business, and not much “regular life” as one would expect when studying abroad; in the next blog post or two I’ll try to touch on more of my daily routine from my first few days in Hangzhou!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bonus Quote&lt;/em&gt;: Our tour guide for this section of the trip (a Beijing native) wanted to explain to the group the symbolic importance of the dragon in Chinese culture. Dragons were creatures of great wealth, saving, and self-sufficiency; they would eat up all of their treasure and store in in their large stomachs without ever releasing it (in the form of feces) again. Or, as our guide phrased it,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The dragon have big mouth and no ass. So, he eat a lot, and don’t do shit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ancient emperors, he said, believed they were dragons in human form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No kidding!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>neill</name></author><category term="china" /><category term="travel" /><category term="personal" /><summary type="html">Who would have guessed that one day I would be saying hello from China? Over the next few weeks, I’ll be doing my best to chronicle my journey through a Study Abroad experience in Hangzhou, across the world from my Raleigh hometown.</summary></entry></feed>